Guide to the Leonard Jimmie Savage Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additions
  - Addition 1977 Sep 2
    - off-print, Scientia Magazine, issue, 1976 May-August (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - xerox copies, obituary from Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, 1972, Class Prophecy, Centralite [High School Yearbook] 1935, acknowledgement for receipt of mathematical journals at Wilkes Barre College, re-publication notices of 2 of Savage's books, one book review mentioning Savage, one letters to the editor column, unidentified. (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Addition 1977 Sep 15
    - "Illustrations of Personal Probability in Insurance," talk delivered 1967 Nov 30 at the Actuarial Conference in New Haven, one reel-to-reel tape and one audio cassette (Box 68)
  - Addition 1978 Jan
    - Audio cassette tape, "Spoken portions of the Memorial Service for Leonard J. Savage", 1972 March (Box 69)
    - Audio tape (reel-to-reel) of the memorial service for L. J. Savage, Yale University, 1972 March (Box 69)
    - "The Shifting Foundations of Statistics," by L.J. Savage in Logic, Laws and Life: Some Philosophical Complications," Robert G. Colodny, editor, University of Pittsburgh Press, 1977 (Box 69)
  - Addition 1978 Jun 8
    preliminary listing by Kathy M.U. Straka 11/22/78
    - "Final Report on The Safety Problem Occasioned by Firing Corporals over U.S. 70," report on firing Corporal missiles at White Sands Proving Ground in vicinity of U.S. Highway 70, coauthored by L. J. Savage, pp. 65., 1954 February 12 (Box 69)
    - Correspondence concerning White Sands report, 1954 of L. J. Savage and Louise Forsyth, 5 items, 1962 January-March (Box 69)
    - Covering letter from Louise Forsyth to I. R. Savage, 1977 December 3 (Box 69)
    - Correspondence regarding White Sands Report, 1954 Feb 12, by William Ericson, Stephen E. Fienberg, Louise Forsyth, Harry V. Roberts, and I. R. Savage, 12 items, 1977-1978 (Box 69)
    - ALS xerox copy in Italian from Corinna [?], former employee to L. J. Savage, Rome, pp. 2, 1977 December 1 (Box 69)
    - Table of Contents for Chapter 3 and pages 196-197 of Evaluation and Experiment edited by Carl A. Bennett and Arthur Lumsdaine, Academic Press, 1975, with a notation by Donald T. Campbell, xerox copy, pp. 2, undated (Box 69)
    - Review of Inequalities on the Probability Content of Convex Regions for Elliptically Contoured Distributions, coauthored by L. J. Savage, Univ. of California Press, 1972, from Mathematical Reviews, xerox copy, 1 p., undated (Box 69)
  - Addition 1978 Nov 9
  - Addition 1980 Sep 8, 1968-1981
    Preliminary inventory by 93 Nancy Fappiano Special Projects 1980 Oct
    Received from I. Richard Savage, 1980 Sep 5
    10 folders
    - Taped interview with Rose Rugowitz Adler (aunt) conducted by Joan Savage Weissmann (sister) concerning Savage family history, 1978 July 12 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified notes from L.J. Savage (given by widow 1979 Sep), undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence between Richard Olshen and I. Richard Savage concerning a manuscript by Morris L. Eaton, 1980 January-April (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - ALS from L. J. Savage to I. Richard Savage, 1968 December 2 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Copy of the biographical sketch of L. J. Savage appearing in the by William H. Kruskal, 1978 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence between Arnold Zellner and I. Richard Savage regarding Leonard Savage Award, 1977 February-March (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence between I. Richard Savage and the International Statistical Institute concerning photograph of L. J. Savage, 1977 October-November (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Reprint (with relative correspondence) of a paper by Paul Samuelson dedicated to L. J. Savage, 1980 February-March (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Copy of "L. J. Savage - His work in Probability and statistics" by D. V. Lindley, 1980 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript copy of reading notes by L. J. Savage, 1961 May 10 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - (*) Also one folder 1982 Aug addition (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1981 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Publications and clippings, 1952-1981 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Addition 1981 Apr, 1940-1981
      Preliminary inventory by Thomas S. Dyman 1981 May
      Received from I. Richard Savage, 1981 Apr 10
      2 archive boxes [nos. 70-71]
      - Correspondence, L.J. Savage literary executor, 1976-1977 (Box 70)
      - Correspondence, "Shifting Foundations", 1970-1977 (Box 70)
      - Correspondence, mathematical reviews, 1972-1975 (Box 70)
      - Correspondence, publication of L.J. Savage memorial volume, 1973-1981 (Box 70)
      - Correspondence and printed materials relating to L.J. Savage, 1970-1981 (Box 70)
      - The American Statistical Association and the Institute of Mathematical Statistics, The Writings of Leonard Jimmie Savage - A Memorial Selection, 1981 (Box 70)
      - Bruno de Finetti e Leonard J. Savage, "Sul modo di scegliere le probabilità iniziali,", 1962
        See: box 43, folder 93
      - L.J. Savage, "Il problema delle strategie ottime di gioco," "Uno sguardo sulla statistica di oggi", 1962
        See: box 44, folder 107
      - L.J. Savage, "On Rereading R.A. Fisher,", 1976 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Probability in Science: A Personalistic Account,", 1973 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "The Application of Vectoral Methods to Metric Geometry", 1946 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "A Dynamic Problem in Duopoly,", 1940 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and Milton Friedman, "The Unexpected Utility Hypothesis and the Measurability of Utility,", 1952 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and R.R. Bahadur, "The Non-existence of Certain Statistical Procedures in Nonparametric Problems,", 1956 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "On the Crossing of Extremals at Focal Points,", 1943 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and R.J. Nunke, "On the Set of Values of a Nonatomic, Finitely Additive, Finite Measure,", 1952
        See: box 43, folder 99
      - L.J. Savage, "Samuelson's Foundations: Its Mathematics", 1948 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Recent Tendencies in the Foundations of Statistics,", 1958
        See: box 44, folder 111
      - L.J. Savage, "A Uniqueness Theorem for Unbiased Sequential Binomial Estimation,", 1947 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "The Theory of Statistical Decision,", 1951 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and James H. Lorie, "Three Problems in Rationing Capital,", 1955 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and Milton Friedman, "The Utility Analysis of Choices Involving Risk,", 1948 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and Edwin Hewitt, "Symmetric Measures on Cartesian Products,", 1955 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "When Different Pairs of Hypotheses Have the Same Family of Likelihood - Ratio Test Regions,", 1957 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and Lester E. Dubins, "Optimal Gambling Systems,", 1957-1958 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "The Foundations of Statistics Reconsidered,", 1961 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Campi di applicazione e tecniche della statistica,", 1962 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and Lester E. Dubins, "A Tchebycheff - like Inequality for Stochastic Processes,", 1965 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Difficulties in the Theory of Personal Probability,", 1967 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Implications of Personal Probability for Induction," [copy in box 42, folder 81], 1967 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "A Geometrical Approach to the Special Stable Distributions,", 1969 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Reading Suggestions for the Foundations of Statistics,", 1970 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage and Richard Olshen, "A Generalized Unimodality,", 1970 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Die bayessche Entwicklungs stuffe der statistischen Schlussweise,", 1968 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Elicitation of Personal Probabilities and Expectations,", 1971 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "The Characteristic Function Characterized and the Momentousness of Movements,", 1971 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, "Diagnosis and the Bayesian Viewpoint," in John A Jacquez, ed., Computer Diagnosis and Diagnostic, Methods, 1972 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, et al., "Inequalities on the Probability Content of Convex Regions for Elliptically Contoured Distributions,", 1971 (Box 71)
      - Ian Hacking, "Slightly More Realistic Personal Probability,", 1967 (Box 71)
      - Kenneth E. Boulding, "Samuelson's Foundations: the Role of Mathematics in Economics", 1948 (Box 71)
      - L.J. Savage, et al, "The Mathematics of Glottochronology Revisited,", 1972 (Box 71)
  - Addition Sep 1979, 1936 - (1959-1970)
    Preliminary inventory by John Espy 1983 Feb
    Received from Mrs. L. Savage, 1979 Sep 14
    1 1/2-archive box (no. 72)
    - Family papers: TL to Frank Savage, calendar, 1965, undated (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and printed matter re: nystagmus, and special eyeglasses, 1956-1964, undated (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Printed matter and notes re: heart, exercise, vitamins, 1968-1970, undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Book file:
      - Deason, Hilary J., comp, and ed.; A Guide to Science Reading, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Dresden, Arnold. An Invitation to Mathematics, 1936 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Harrower, Molly. Time to Squander, Time to Reap, 1946 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Addition 1982 Aug, 1952-(1966-1981)
    Preliminary inventory by Marcy Graham Murphy 1982 Sep
    Received from: I. Richard Savage, 1982 Aug 31
    - Booklet: Metoda di Lingua Italiana by Stranieri, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Correspondence to and from Bruno de Finetti, 1977-1979 (Box 68)
    - Correspondence, most to or from I. Richard Savage, 1966-1981 (Box 68)
    - Publications and clippings, 1979-1981 (Box 68)
  - Addition 1982 Nov 22
  - Correspondence between L. J. Savage and R. A. Fischer, 1952-1958 (Box 68)
  - Addition 1983 Jun, 1961 - (1971-1977)
    Preliminary inventory by Robert Raffeld 1983 Jun
    Received from I. Richard Savage; June 1983
    The bulk of the material in this addition consists of correspondence between I. Richard Savage as executor of the L. J. S. estate and others. Much of the material is related to the Memorial Service held for L. J. S. in 1972 at Dwight Chapel, the Leonard J. Savage Memorial Book Fund, and the L. J. S. Archives at Yale University. There is also a considerable amount of correspondence between I. R. S. and Lester Dubins about the re-publication of How to Gamble If You Must, co-authored by Dubins and L. J. S.
    - Allen, Garrott, 1971, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Amato, Barbara, 1971-1972 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Anscombe, Francis, 1971-1972 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - B, 1971-1973 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - C, 1972, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Dover Publications, 1971-1975 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Dubins, Lester, 1971-1976 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      See also: box 73, Folder 6 See also: box 73, Folder 16
    - E, 1972-1975 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - F, 1971-1975 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Jaquez, John, 1972-1973 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - K, 1972-1973 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Kruskal, William, 1972-1976 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Lindley, Dennis, 1973-1975 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Marschak, Jacob, 1974-1975 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - McGraw-Hill Publishing Co., 1972 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - North-Holland Publishing Co., 1975 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Olkin, Ingram, 1972, 1974, 1977 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - P, 1971, 1973, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - R, 1971-1972 (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Re: Literary executor, 1971-1972, 1975, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Re: Medical records of L. J. S., 1972 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Re: Memorial service; memorial fund; biographical notes on L. J. S., 1971-1972 (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - Re: Secondary education of L. J. S., 1972 (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - S, 1972, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - Savage Family, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 25)
    - Savage, Jean, 1971-1972 (Box 73, Folder 26)
    - University Microfilms Xerox Co., 1972, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 27)
    - V, 1972, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 28)
    - W, 1971-1974 (Box 73, Folder 29)
    - Wallis, W. A., 1972, 1974 (Box 73, Folder 30)
    - Yale University Library, 1972-1976 (Box 73, Folder 31)
    - Zellner, Arnold, 1975, 1977 (Box 73, Folder 32)
    - Unidentified correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 73, Folder 33)
    - Article: "An Overview of Modern Statistics" by L. J. S., 1961 (Box 73, Folder 34)
    - Duplicate letters and notes of L. J. S. (Box 73, Folder 35)
  - Addition 1983 Oct, 1964-1970
    Preliminary Inventory by Tina Evans 1983 Nov
    Received from: I. Richard Savage, 26 October 1983
    1 1/2 archive box
  - Class Lectures
    - Bayesian Inference With Many Nuisance Parameters Stanford - Berkeley Seminar, 1964 February 8 (Box 74)
    - The Hypergeometric Distribution: A Review Derivation, Mathematics 41A, 1966 October 18 (Box 74)
    - The Factorial Function, Mathematics 47A, 1968 November 11 (Box 74)
    - On Some Conventions That Seem Useful, by Bruno di Finetti, translated by LJS, 1969 January 28 (Box 74)
    - The Expected-Upcrossing Inequality for Expection Decreasing Semimartingales, Statistics - 100, 1969 February 20 (Box 74)
  - Teaching Materials
    - A combinatorial problem for David T. Chou, 1969 December 30 (Box 74)
    - Answer sheet for selected problems in chapters 4, 5, and 7, Mathematics and Statistics, 42b/205, 1970 May 5 (Box 74)
    - Dissertation, Robert Ling, with LJS's comments, 1970 March 5 (Box 74)
    - Audio cassette, LJS's comments on R. Ling's, dissertation, 1969 or 1970 (Box 74)
  - Addition 1984 Jul, 1971, 1983
    Preliminary inventory by John Espy 1985 Feb
    Received from: I. Richard Savage, 1984 Jul 6
    - L.J. Savage, ALS to Dr. and Mrs. Ion Petrea, 1971 (Box 74)
    - I. Richard Savage, copies of correspondence with William Kruskal, with copy of article by J. Garrott Allen, "The Use of Statistics to Achieve Blood Labeling", 1983 (Box 74)
    - Copies of letters from Stephen M. Stigler to Milton Friedman, with copy of review by R.A. Fisher of Keynes' treatise on probability, 1983 (Box 74)
  - Correspondence: George Kubler (1985), William Kruskal (1983), Robert Ling (1983), and Arnold Zellner (1983-1985); Collected reviews (1982-1985), and Springer-Verlag calendar. (Box 74)
  - Review by Leonard J. Savage for American Statistical Association Journal (v. 50), 1955 December (Box 49A, Folder 174)
    Accession 1989-M-012
    Received from: I. Richard Savage, 1988 Jul 1
- Additional Material, 1943-1973, 1982, undated; Accession 1990-M-045; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1990 Apr 2
  Received from: I. Richard Savage, 1989 Dec 13
  - Personal correspondence, 1944-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Professional correspondence, 1951-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence of others, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Papers relating to the death, funeral, and memorial service of Leonard Jimmie Savage, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Announcement of selection as fellow of American Statistical Association, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Announcements of addresses, 1963, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Review of book about Leonard Jimmie Savage, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial and medical records, 1943-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, undated; Accession 1991-M-017; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1990 Aug
  Received from: I. Richard Savage, 1990 Aug 3
  - Listing of reprints of others, undated (Box 1)
  - Excerpt from The Cybernetics Group by Steve J. Heims: with correspondence to/from I. Richard Savage, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - "The St. Petersburg paradox and bounded utility," by Gilbert W. Bassett, Jr.: with correspondence to/from I. Richard Savage, 1992 August (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1991-1992; Accession 1993-M-067; .05 linear feet (2 folders)
  Received from: I. Richard Savage, 1993 Apr 14
  Added to Accession 1991-M-017
- Additional Material, 1949-1972, undated; Accession 1993-M-077; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition Inventory by Carol King 1993 Jul
  Received from: Jean Savage, 1993 May 24
  - Algebraic calculations, handwritten, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Statistical Association: lecture announcements, 1963, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Boolean algebra, paper on the subject of, 1960 August (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Condolence letters to Jean Savage, 1971 October-1972 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, professional, 1951-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reading notes, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Security questionnaires, correspondence: Rand Corporation, 1949-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Subjective Basis of Statistical Practices, draft, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yale University: appointments, leaves of absence, salary, miscellaneous, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, 1925-1976, undated; Accession 1993-M-083; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1994 Apr
  Received from: John W. Pratt, 1992 Oct 13
  This addition to the Leonard J. Savage Papers pertains to Savage's manuscript, "On Rereading R. A. Fisher." The paper was presented originally as an R. A. Fisher Memorial Lecture in Detroit on December 29, 1970 under the auspices of the American Statistical Association, the Institute of Mathematical Statistics, and the Biometric Society. The paper was edited for publication by John W. Pratt of Harvard University after Leonard J. Savage's untimely death on November 1, 1971. The paper was published in The Annals of Statistics, vol. 4, no. 3, 1976.
  - Correspondence
    - R. A. Fisher and L. J. Savage, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - R. A. Fisher and John W. Tukey, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - John Pratt and L. J. Savage, 1958-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
    - John Pratt and I. R. Savage, 1971 December-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - John Pratt and others, 1972-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 7-11)
    - I. R. Savage and Frank Anscombe, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - L. J. Savage and others, 1953, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Joan Savage and others, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Drafts, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15-20)
  - Original footnotes (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Pratt, John: editorial notes, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Reviews of "On Rereading R. A. Fisher", 1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Articles and reviews by R. A. Fisher, 1925-1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "F. Y. Edgeworth and R. A. Fisher on the Efficiency of Maximum Likelihood Estimation," by John Pratt (with accompanying correspondence), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Articles by others about the work of R. A. Fisher, 1935-1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bibliographies/indices of works by R. A. Fisher, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "Fisher Memorial Lecture," by L. J. Savage: transcript of tape, [1970] (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - "Fisher Project, Random Notes", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Additional Material, Accession 1996-M-004
  - Correspondence
    - Stigler, Stephen, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Woodroofe, Michael [Leonard J. Savage Collegiate Professor of Statistics, University of Michigan], 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Zellner, Arnold, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter of condolence from Mary Griswold with accompanying report, "Eliminating Racial Imbalance in Connecticut Public Schools" [project in which L.J. Savage participated], 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-109
  See Accession 1996-M-004, box 1, folder 4